Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
Rudin (Gail and Stephen) Slavery Collection,
- Series XI: Newspapers
  - "The Boston Evening Post" debating the slave trade in Colonial America, September 21, 1772; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 868
  - Gazette of the United States and Philadelphia Daily Advertiser-Runaway Slave Ads, January 1, 1800; Location: Pennsylvania (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rudin Newspaper #1
  - "Windham Herald"- Will of Gen. George Washington, March 6, 1800 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rudin Newspaper #2
  - "City Gazette and Daily Advertiser" - Ads for Sale of Slave, May 4, 1801; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rudin Newspaper #3
  - "Columbian Centinel" - Thomas Jefferson and Sally Hemmings, September 11, 1802; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rudin Newspaper #3a
  - "New York Evening Post" containing advertisements for slaves for purchase, November 17, 1802; Location: New York (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 605B
  - "Relfs Philadelphia Gazette and Advertiser" Reward Offered for Runaway, February 7, 1803; Location: Pennsylvania (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rudin Newspaper #4
  - "Charleston Courier" with slavery related ads, January 10, 1805; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 981
  - "The Enquirer" with slaves for sale, February 18, 1806; Location: Richmond, Virginia (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Rudin Newspaper #5
  - "Newburyport Herald" - Debate on the Bill Prohibiting the African Slave Trade, January 13, 1807 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Rudin Newspaper #6
  - "Charleston Courier" numerous cargoes of slaves offered for sale, February 18, 1807; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 1003
  - "Charleston Courier" with illustrated slave ads, June 24, 1807; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 1004
  - "Columbia Centinel" description of an advertisement for runaway slave, October 7, 1807; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 929
  - "The Star" Runaway Slave Ad, January 4, 1810; Location: Raleigh, North Carolina (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Rudin Newspaper #7
  - "Richmond Enquirer", "The Lynchburg Press", "Daily Republican Banner" (4 newspapers), 1818, 1821, 1838; Location: Richmond, Lynchburg, Nashville (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 920
  - "Richmond Enquirer" slave ads, October 9, 1818; Location: Richmond, Virginia (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Rudin Newspaper #8
  - "Boston Recorder", March 13, 1819; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Rudin Newspaper #9
  - "Richmond Enquirer," including runaway slave ads and announcement of sale of "44 Negroes" as part of the estate Romancock, May 26, 1818; Location: Richmond, Virginia (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Newspaper #10
  - "City Gazette and Commercial Daily Advertiser", March 15 and June 13, 1820; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Rudin Newspaper #10, 11
  - "The Charleston Courier" -Rewards for Runaways, August 7, 1820; Location: South Carolina (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Rudin Newspaper #12
  - "Niles Weekly Register" - throwing slaves overboard in casks to lighten slave ship, August 4, 1821; Location: Baltimore, Maryland (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 814
  - "The Genius of Liberty" -Rewards for Runaways, November 27, 1821; Location: Virginia (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Rudin Newspaper #13
  - The Compiler - 40 slave-related ads, January 4-7, 1822 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 828
  - "Washington Gazette" contains chart presenting results of 1820 census, January 17, 1822; Location: Washington, DC (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 951
  - "National Intelligencer", August 31, 1822; Location: Washington, DC (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Rudin Newspaper #14
  - "Southern Patriot and Commercial Advertiser", February 11, 1825; Location: South Carolina (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Rudin Newspaper #15
  - "National Intelligencer" -Notice for Runaway, Public Sale, October 10, 1826; Location: Washington DC (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Rudin Newspaper #16
  - "Richmond Enquirer", November 7, 1826; Location: Virginia (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Rudin Newspaper #16a
  - "New-Hampshire Statesman and Concord Register", December 16, 1826; Location: New Hampshire (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Rudin Newspaper #16b
  - "Daily National Intelligencer", February 12, 1825; Location: Washington (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Rudin Newspaper #17
  - "The Globe", October 11 and October 13, 1831; Location: Washington, DC5 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 829, 786
  - "Niles' Weekly Register" - reports at length the anti-abolitionist riots of 1834 in New York City, July 19, 1834; Location: Baltimore, Maryland (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 955
  - "Niles' Weekly Register" - reports on the three-day Philadelphia race riots, August 23, 1834; Location: Baltimore, Maryland (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Niles' Weekly Register" - Facts on Slavery written with a positive view, September 27, 1834; Location: Baltimore, Maryland (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 954
  - "Niles' Weekly Register" reports how the African King Boatswain brutally delivers slaves to the European traders, July 11, 1835; Location: Baltimore, Maryland (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 787
  - "Newark Daily Advertiser" -detailed report of a fugitive slave case, August 18, 1836; Location: Newark, New Jersey (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 988
  - "Daily National Intelligencer", May 2, 1838; Location: Washington, DC (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Rudin Newspaper #17a
  - Group of over 60 "Harper's Weekly" and "Frank Leslie's Illustrated", 1840s-1890s; Location: New York (Box 27)
    Rudin # S - 713
  - "National Intelligencer" Amistad case, March 16, 1841; Location: Washington, DC (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 749
  - "The Daily Atlas", November 8, 1841; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Rudin Newspaper #17b
  - "Herald of Freedom" Published by the New Hampshire Anti-Slavery Society, June 9, 1843; Location: Concord, New Hampshire (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Rudin Newspaper #18
  - "The Louisville Daily Journal" five issues, February-March, 1844; Location: Louisville, Kentucky (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 906
  - "The Liberator" liberated slaves, April 25, 1845; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 700
  - 5 abolitionist newspapers "Pennsylvania Freeman", "The Declaration of Independence", "The cradle of Liberty", "The True American", "The Delaware Abolitionist", 1839-1848; Location: Pennsylvania, Ohio, Massachusetts, Kentucky, Delaware (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 676
  - "New York Daily Tribune" supplement, May 11, 1850; Location: New York (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 792
  - "New York Daily Tribune", June 1, 1850; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 701
  - "Fayetteville Observer", March 11, 1851; Location: Fayetteville, North Carolina (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 830
  - "Gleason's Pictorial", February 14, 1852; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "The New York Weekly Tribune" eyewitness of a slave auction in Richmond, March 19, 1853; Location: New York (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 811
  - "New York Daily Times" three issues, 1854; Location: New York (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 793
  - "Portland Pleasure Boat", February 8, 1855; Location: Maine (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Rudin Newspaper #19
  - "Daily Union", May 4 and 5, 1855; Location: Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 961, 1000
  - "Wilmington Journal" -Runaway Slave Notice, November 2, 1855; Location: North Carolina (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Rudin Newspaper #20
  - "The Louisville Daily Journal" five issues, May 2-26, 1856; Location: Louisville, Kentucky (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 832
  - "The Daily Picayune", 2 issues, July 1856; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 959
  - "New York Daily Times" slave auction in New Orleans, November 4, 1856; Location: New York (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 762
  - "The Charleston Daily Courier" -Notice Regarding Issuing Slave Badges, January 18, 1858; Location: South Carolina (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Rudin Newspaper #21
  - "The Daily Journal", June 12, 20 1858; Location: Wilmington, North Carolina (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Rudin Newspaper #21a, 22
  - "The Daily Picayune", March 19, 1859; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 1005
  - "Daily True Delta" slave auction advertisements, November 24, 1859; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 841
  - "Daily True Delta" -Valuable Slaves at Auction, March 14, 1860; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Rudin Newspaper #23
  - "The Liberator", May 4, 1860; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 750
  - "Harper's Weekly" slave ship engravings, wildfire, June 2, 1860; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 682
  - "Frank Leslie's Illustrated" reporting 750 rescued slaves, June 23, 1860; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 788
  - "National Anti-Slavery Standard" with voting ballot showing Lincoln winning, June 26, 1860; Location: New York (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 834
  - "Harper's Weekly" Lincoln political cartoon, August 25, 1860; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 757
  - "New York Weekly Tribune" fugitive slave shipped in box, September 8, 1860; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 889
  - "Harper's Weekly", July 13, 1861; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 789
  - "Harper's Weekly" three issues, 1862-1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 752
  - "Frank Leslie's Illustrated", February 1, 1862; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 790
  - "The Pilot" Lincoln advocates gradual emancipation, March 15, 1862; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 711
  - The Daily Intelligencer- two pages, list of clamants petitioning the Emancipation Commission. Includes names and numbers of slaves, April 16, 1862; Location: District of Columbia (Frame 1)
    Rudin # S - 209
  - "Harper's Weekly" slaves loading cannon, May 10, 1862; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 910
  - "National Intelligencer" ten issues, 1862; Location: Washington, DC (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 753, 758
  - "The New York Tribune" Greeley's prayer and Lincoln's response, August, 1862; Location: New York (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 771
  - "Harper's Weekly" Vicksburg Slaves, August 2, 1862; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 962
  - "Leavenworth Daily Conservative", August 12, 1862; Location: Leavenworth, Kansas (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 815
  - "The Evening Post", August 19, 1862; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 709
  - "New York Observer" Commodore Foote, October 2, 1862; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 873
  - "The Evening Post", December 5, 1862; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 710
  - "Daily Dispatch", December 27, 1862; Location: Richmond, Virginia (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 1002
  - "New York Herald" slave and free states, January 4, 1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 759
  - "Frank Leslie's Illustrated", January 31, May 9, 1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 703
  - "New York Tribune", February 7, 1863; Location: New York (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 798
  - "Southern Confederacy", ca. 1863 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 605E
  - "The Daily Guardian of Paterson, New Jersey", May 2, 1863; Location: Paterson, New Jersey (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 605F
  - "The Liberator", May 15, 1863; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 912
  - "Harper's Weekly" Slave Gordon, July 4, 1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 726
  - "New York Tribune", July 15, 1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 675
  - "Frank Leslie's Illustrated", July 25, 1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 838
  - "The New York Tribune" two issues, draft riot coverage, July, 1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 668
  - "New York Daily Tribune" - six issues, draft riot coverage, July, 1863; Location: New York (Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 1042A-1042G
  - "Harper's Weekly" draft riots, August 1, 1863; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 837
  - "The New York Herald" two issues, August 11, 1863; September 24, 1864; Location: New York (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 736, 737
  - "Sacramento Daily Union" - White slaves of the south, September 12, 1863; Location: Sacramento, California (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 1001
  - "Tri-Weekly telegraph", with advertisement for slave auction, November 10, 1863; Location: Houston, Texas (Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 1048
  - "New York Daily Tribune" 6 issues, January, 1864; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 781
  - "Harper's Weekly" - Colored Troops Under Gen. Wild Liberating Slaves in North Carolina", January 23, 1864; Location: New York (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 560
  - "Harper's Weekly" Emancipated slaves, January 30, 1864; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 888
  - "The Liberator" -Miscegenation and Amalgamation Articles, April 8, 1864; Location: Boston, Massachusetts (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Rudin Newspaper #24
  - "Frank Leslie's Illustrated" colored troops in action, July 9, 1864; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 963
  - "The Daily Conservative of Leavenworth" Call to arms for colored men, July 31, 1864; Location: Leavenworth, Kansas (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 605D
  - Lithographed Broadsheet in Commemoration of Emancipation in Maryland, November 1, 1864; Location: Ringwalt and Brown Philadelphia Format: Lithograph (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 434
  - "The Charleston Mercury", January 26, 1865; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 747
  - "Florida Union", April 1, 1865; Location: Jacksonville, Florida (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 795
  - "The New York Times" three issues, May, 1865; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 611
  - "The New York Times" -Slavery Forever Dead in the United States, December 19, 1865; Location: (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Rudin Newspaper #25
  - Farewell Issue of William Lloyd Garrison's "The Liberator", December 29, 1865; Location: Boston; Format: "News- Paper" (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 561
  - "Harper's Weekly" two issues, 1866; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 704
  - Harper's Weekly - Article and Picture of "Blind Tom", February 10, 1866; Location: New York; Format: "News- Paper" (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 504
  - "Harper's Weekly" - The Horror of Fugitive Slave Margaret Garner, May 18, 1867; Location: New York (Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 1028
  - "Harper's Weekly", September 14, 1867; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 605C
  - La Rue's Minstrels: the Model Troupe of the World, 1869; Format: PRINT (Frame 2)
    Rudin # S - 485
  - Harper's Weekly - Group of 10 Prints, 1870s-1880s; Location: New York (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 415
  - "Harper's Weekly" slave ship, April 25, 1874; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 919
  - "Harper's Weekly", October 28, 1876; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 937
  - "Harper's Weekly" five issues, 1879; Location: New York (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 686
- Series XII: Officers' Pay Vouchers
  - Pay Vouchers with servants listed (Zachary Taylor), 1846 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 84
  - U.S. Colored Troops pay vouchers (3) for officers with servants, 1861-1865 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 45
  - Pay Vouchers (8) for officers with servants, 1861-1865 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 45a
  - Pay Voucher for Lt John Floyd (65th Illinois Infantry) and his Black Servant, May 25, 1864; Location: Louisville, Kentucky Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 507
- Series XIII: Pamphlets and Printed Documents
  - British Colonial American Act Making Lands, Houses and Negroes Liable for the Satisfaction of Debts, 1732; Location: London Format: Imprint (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 526
  - Legalized Slave Shipments from Jamaica, 1766; Location: London Format: Ptd DOC (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 381
  - Extract from an address by Arthur Lee calling for the end of slavery, March 19, 1787; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 690
  - An act to prevent the slave trade in acts and laws passed by the general court of Massachusetts, May 31, 1787; Location: Massachusetts Format: Ptd Docs (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 691
  - America's first census report, October 24, 1791; Location: Printed in Philadelphia Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 853
  - Address of the American Convention for Promoting the Abolition of Slavery and Improving the Condition of the African Race, 1804; Location: Philadelphia Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 596
  - American Colonization Society Petitions Congress to create a colony for free blacks, January 14, 1817; Location: Washington, DC Format: Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 992
  - Naval Pamphlet Requesting Bounty for Slaves Captured during War of 1812, January 8, 1821; Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 224
  - American Colonization Society Booklet - "The African Repository and Colonial Journal", November 1829; Location: Washington City Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 493
  - Suppression of the Slave Trade, May 22, 1826; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 272
  - American Colonization Society Speech seeking government aid for the Society, January 20, 1827; Location: Washington, D.C. Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 204
  - Group of 29 Government documents dealing with slavery, 1828-1850, 1867; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Doc (Box 34)
    Rudin # S - 634
  - Causes that Lead to the Formation of the Colonization Society - Pamphlet, 1832; Location: Philadelphia Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 245
  - Fifth Census-using the "3/5 Slave Rule" to Determine Representation in the House, January 4, 1832; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 266
  - "Right and Wrong in Boston" - Report of the Boston Female Anti-Slavery Society, 1836; Location: Boston Format: Book (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 1015
  - Broadside advertises Henry Muhlenberg defense of his house servant against fugitive slave charges, February 28, 1836; Location: Reading, Pennsylvania (?) Format: Broadside (Box 8, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 1016
  - Speech to the senate by Senator Preston, regarding the abolition question, March 1, 1836; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Doc (Box 8, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 871
  - Government imprints relating to slave ship and creating the first US African Squadron, February 14, 1837; December 30, 1842; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Doc (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 949
  - American Colonization Society Printed Circular Letter - Convening 22nd Annual Meeting and Outlining New Constitution, October 17, 1838; Location: Washington Format: Ptd Letter (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 347
  - Quaker Slavery and Abolition Broadside, April 19, 1839; Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Format: Ptd DOC (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 326
  - Abolitionist Booklet Illuminating the Quakers' Commitment to the Fight Against Slavery, 1839; Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 563
  - Congressional resolution authorizing circuit judges to surrender fugitives from justice, 1840; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 8, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 606C
  - Granting Papers to Vessels Engaged in the Slave Trade, January 20, 1841; Location: Washington, DC Format: Book (Box 8, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S -273
  - Benedict's Statement on Conditions in Liberia, September 14, 1841; Location: New York Format: Ptd Docs (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 365
  - Congressional pamphlet relating to the issue of black mariners arriving in South Carolina ports and facing imprisonment, ca. 1842; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Pamphlet (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 580
  - Speech of Francis Scott Key before the Colonization Convention, May 9, 1842; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 211
  - Funding the Shipment of Slaves to Africa, March 25, 1843; Location: Washington Format: Ptd Letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 317
  - Third Annual Report of the Massachusetts Colonization Society, May 29, 1844; Location: Massachusetts Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 354
  - Tavern Keeper's Bond, re: Will not sell liquor to slaves, November 1, 1846; Location: Format: (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 8
  - Circular for the "Free Produce Store" - "No Slave Labour products will be knowingly kept in his store", 1847; Location: N.W. Corner of Fifth and Cherry Streets Format: Ptd DOC (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 503
  - Resolution that Slavery be Prohibited in any New Territory that may be Acquired, February 16, 1847; Location: The Legislature of Pennsylvania (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 583
  - Passage of law enabling citizens of slave holding states to recover slaves escaping into non-slave holding states, 1848; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 606D
  - Gerrit Smith Details his Position on Support for Anti-Slavery Candidates, August 15, 1848; Location: Peterboro Format: Ptd CIRCULAR (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 582
  - Proposed state senate legislation to deal with "free Negroes and Mulattoes", April 8, 1852; Location: Maryland Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 630
  - Circular of the Missouri Colonization Society stating its purpose and requesting funds, May 31, 1852; Location: St. Louis, Missouri Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 927
  - Putnam's Plan for the Formation of Rural Districts in Liberia, December 1, 1852; Location: New York Format: Ptd Broadside (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 321
  - First Annual Report New York Anti-Slavery Society, May 12, 1854; Location: New York Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 355
  - Fugitive Slave Broadside - Underground Railroad, July 2, 1855; Location: Anti-Slavery Office Albany, New York Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 205
  - Report of the 24th National Anti-Slavery festival, 1858; Location: Boston, Massachusetts Format: Booklet (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 719
  - "Instructions to the African Squadron" as to how to deter slave trade, March 1, 1859; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 833
  - Negotiation of a treaty with Great Britain for surrender of fugitive slaves, 1860; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 606A
  - The secession of South Carolina and the ordinance of secession booklet, 1860; Location: Charleston, South Carolina Format: Booklet (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 706
  - "The Address to the People of South Carolina Assembled in Convention, to the People of the Slaveholding States of the United States", 1860; Location: Charleston, South Carolina Format: Ptd Booklet (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 851
  - "Statement of the Sugar Crop made in Louisiana, in 1859-1860", 1860; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: Booklet (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 977